[
   {
    "tutorial":
    [["Welcome to the Loops World!\nOne of the more important aspects of writing computer code is to keep it as short as possible.\nWhen you have to repeat a the same code you can write it once and use a LOOP.\nLoops puts the code in a special block allowing it to repeat doing that same block of code from the beginning. They use conditions(like if statements) everytime check if they should run that special {block} of code.\nHeres how they work:\n\t1. Check if condition is true\n\t\tIf it is true run the block of code\n\t\twhen finish go back to 1. repeat.\n\tIf NOT true don't run the block of code.\n\n There are different types of loops, today you will be looking at WHILE and FOR loops.\n"],
    ["Let start with the WHILE loops\nThe WHILE LOOP is used when you don't know how may times to repeat to code but you do know a condition(if statement) to stop it.\n\tWHILE(condition = true)\n\t\t{repeat this block of code}\n If it is true it will run again but it it is false it will stop.\nHere is an example:\n\t{%strong%}Today = Wednesday\n\tWHILE(Weekday)\n\t\t{you go to school\n\t\tyou come back home\n\t\tyou do your homework\n\t\tyou play\n\t\ttoday = tomorrow}\nThis code will repeat 3 times, for wednesday, thursday, friday, on saturday the condion is false stop."],
    ["Lets learn about the FOR loops. The FOR loops are used when you know the number of times you want to repeat the block of code.\nhere is how it looks\n\tFOR(start counter = 0; counter less than Number; add 1 to counter )\n\t{ repeat this block of code }\nHere is how it works\n1. It starts the counter at 0.\n 2. check if counter is less than Number\n3. If true do Block of code and go to step 4.. If False stop.\n4. add 1 to counter\n5. repeat step 2.\nHere is an example, Lets say you want to buy a toy that cost 5 dollars but you dont have any money. and your parents are going to pay you 1 dollar for doing chores.\n\tFOR(counter = 0; counter less than 5; add 1 to counter )\n\t\t{do chores}\nThis program will run 5 times untill you have 5 dollars to buy the toy."]
    ,["x"],["x"],["x"]],
    "optionNum": 0
   },
   {
    "question":
    "You’ve arrived at the next planet. Before landing you have to wait for there to be sunlight over the landing zone. According to the ship computer, sunlight will be over the landing zone in 15 minutes. You set a timer to let you know.\n\tWHILE timer is NOT EQUAL to 15 minutes,\n\t\twait one more minute.\n\tThen you can land your spaceship.\nYou wait for 13 minutes. Does this mean you can land now?\n",
    "optionNum": 2,
    "option1": "Yes",
    "option2": "No",
    "answer": "No"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "You wait 2 more minutes and then begin your descent toward the planet. You land on the planet. Before you can leave the ship the temperature outside needs to increase to a safer level.\n\tWHILE the temperature is LESS than 4 degrees celsius,\n\t\ttemperature increases 1 degrees celsius.\n\tThen you can depart.\n The temperature is currently 2 degrees celsius. How many loops through the cycle do you have to wait?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "2",
     "option2": "3",
     "answer": "2"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "You leave the ship and start to explore the planet. You decide to look at a neighboring valley. The valley is about a 100 meters from your location.\n\tWHILE the distance to the valley is GREATER THAN zero meters,\n\t\tmove 1 meter closer to the valley.\n\tThen you can start exploring the valley.\n You travel 102 meters. Does this mean you have arrived at the valley?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "Yes",
     "option2": "No",
     "answer": "Yes"
    },
   {
     "question":
     "You start to explore the valley by gathering samples of vegetation. You will need 3 samples to complete your mission objective.\n\tWHILE sample size is NOT equal to 3,\n \t\tcollect 1 vegetation sample.\n\tThen you will have completed the task.\nYou find one sample. How many more loop cycles will you have to complete?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "2",
     "option2": "3",
     "answer": "2"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "It looks like you also need to gather rock samples. You will need at least 4 samples to complete this mission objective.\n\tWHILE sample size is LESS THANS OR EQUAL to 4,\n \t\tcollect 1 rock sample.\n\tThen you will have completed the task.\nYou find  2 rock samples. How many more loop cycles will you have to complete?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "2",
     "option2": "3",
     "answer": "2"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "While exploring the valley, you run into an old friend, space explorer C-137.  He needs your help finding some crystals. He need 5 crystals.\n\tFOR (when you start off zero,repeat until you have the right amount),\n\t\tCollect one crystal.\n\tThen you will have completed your task.\nHow many loop cycles must you complete to finish the task?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "5",
     "option2": "6",
     "answer": "5"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "C-137 thanks you and heads off. You decide walk back to your ship. It is about 125 meters away.\n\tFOR (when your current distance is 125 from destination, repeat 123 times),\n \t\ttake one step toward the spaceship\n\tThen you will reach you destination.\nAccording to this loop will you reach your spaceship?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "Yes",
     "option2": "No",
     "answer": "No"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "You reach your spaceship. You decide it is time to return home. You place your destination in the ship’s computer where it will calculate the path. It will take 5 minutes for the computer to finish.\n\tFOR (time is currently at 0 minutes, repeat 5 time),\n\t\twait 1 minute.\n\tThen the computer will be finished.\nAccording to this loop will the ships computer be finished?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "No",
     "option2": "Yes",
     "answer": "Yes"
   },
   {
     "question":
     "Before you can liftoff, you have to wait for an opening in the clouds. The computer indicates an opening in 10 minutes. You set a timer.\n\tFOR (timer is at zero, repeat 10 times)\n\t\twait 1 minute.\n\tThen you are ready for liftoff.\nWill this loop complete the timer?\n",
     "optionNum": 2,
     "option1": "Yes",
     "option2": "No",
     "answer": "Yes"
   },
   {
     "question": "Leaving world",
     "optionNum": 0
   },
   {
     "question": "Wrong: Try agian",
     "optionNum": 0
   }
 ]
